Finding Aid for the Photograph Album Collection LSC.0094
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Pasadena tournament of roses., [1990s?]; no.95b; (1 vol., 14 × 17.5 cm. Photograph album with 13 photographs)
  An early Tournament of Roses Parade, pre-automobile, with flower decorated carriages, wagons, and bicycles.
- Tourist's album. v.p., 1898; no.95c; (1 vol., 25 × 34 cm. Photograph album with more than 200 photographs)
  Photos of France, Italy, and Egypt, most of them by Alinari (Italy), Beato (Egypt), N.D. (France) and Zangaki (Egypt). Annotations indicate that the album was assembled in 1898, although the photographs were undoubtedly taken at an earlier date.
- City architecture in France. Paris., circa 1890; no.96; (1 vol., 54 × 45 cm. Photograph album with photographs mounted on canvas)
  Showing examples of the exteriors of French apartment houses and shops.
- French architecture. v.p. (France)., circa 1890; no.97; (1 vol., 54 × 45 cm. Photograph album with photographs mounted on canvas)
  Showing examples of the exteriors of public buildings including schools, museums, theatres, civic buildings, and the Paris Exposition of 1889. Some of the photographs are by N.D. Photographie.
- Santa Barbara photograph album., circa 1899; no.98/1A; (1 album. 14.5 × 26 cm. Snapshot album)
  Unidentified people and views.
  A negative is available of p.62.
- Snapshot album. v.p., circa 1905; no.98/1B; (1 album, 16.5 × 25 cm.)
  Photographs of people and places in the United States, many of them in California.
- Snapshot album. California., circa 1905; no.98/1C; (1 album, 15 × 32 cm.)
  Photographs of people and places in California, some of the places identified.
- Uplifters ninth annual outing. Los Angeles., 1922; no.98/1D; (Photograph album, 20 × 27 cm.)
  Contains photographs of members in groups on various occasions. Among them are some photographs which include Harry Marston Haldeman, founder of the organization.
  Ex-libris: Simeon Crabill.
- Miscellany., no.99; (3 boxes with 4 packages containing 10 vol. of photograph albums)
  A collection of unidentified photograph albums of people and places [99/5 Views of England and Wales].
- Spanish colonial or adobe architecture of California, 1800-1850. New York: Architectural Book Publishing., [c. 1931]; no.100a; (110pp., 28 cm.)
  Extra-illustrated with photographs.
  Ex-libris: Constance Ward.
- British photographs., 1850s[?]; no.100b; (1 album with mounted photographs of various sizes)
  Depicting a country estate somewhere in the British isles with views of the house, some of the outbuildings, the residents, and various scenes of a deer hunt.
  Ex-libris: C.K. Ogden.
- Munsey albums. v.p. (California)., circa 1900; no.101a; (2 vol. 16 × 23 cm. Photograph albums with approximately 200 photographs)
  Issued by Munsey. The emphasis is Southern California, but included are photographs of the Missions and other places of interest.
  Ex-libris: Hazard-Dyson.
- California Album. v.p. (California)., circa 1880s; no.101b; (1 vol., 24 × 30 cm. with 85 mounted photographs [11 × 19 cm.], mounted 2 to a page)
  Commercial photographs showing the Los Angeles area, Pasadena, Mt. Lowe, Redondo, and Yosemite.
- German beer stein collection [n.p. (Germany?)]., [n.d.]; no.102; (1 album. 13 × 19 cm. Photographs)
  Photographs of 45 lidded ceramic steins along with several jars and mugs. All have numbers suggesting that they belong to a collection, although there is no other identification.
- Seashore views. v.p. (England)., 1890s[?]; no.103; (1 vol., 37 × 29 cm. Photograph album)
- Falkland Palace, exterior views. Scotland., circa 1880s[?]; no.104; (9 Unmounted albumen prints)
  The 15th century palace of the Stuarts. The photographs are identified in the plates: 4 by A.Y.; 2 by J[ames] V[alentine]; 3 by G[eorge] W[ashington] W[ilson].
- Italy and Italian art works. v.p. (Italy)., [circa 1870s]; no.105; (16 unmounted albumen prints, mostly 20 × 25 cm.)
  Examples of the popular tourist photographs of the 19th century.
- Santa Cruz and surroundings. Sketches from nature [Santa Cruz, California]., [circa 1863]; no.106; (1 album. 14 × 21 cm. 16 photographs, approximately 9.5 × 12.5 cm. Clipped and mounted)
  Probably from various sources. Included is the above title page.
- Scottish photograph album. v.p., 1890s[?]; no.107; (1 vol. 27 × 23 cm. with 60 photographs mounted in an album lacking its covers)
  Many are signed in the plate by James Valentine or George Washington Wilson. Included are a small group of photographs of art works.
- Album furr Jaeger un Jagdliebhaber. Cassel, Th. Fischer's Verlag ..., 1868; no.108; (1 vol. 31 × 40.5 cm. with 11 photographs, 16.5 × 23 cm.)
  Of painting from Deiker's Jagd-album, 1864, mounted and loose in a portfolio.
- Landscape architecture album. v.p. (California)., 1930s[?]; no.109; (1 album. 24.5 × 30 cm. Approximately 150 photographs)
  A reference collection for a working landscape architect showing examples of pergolas, seats, and other garden structures.
  Ex-libris: George A. Kern.
- Carte-de-visite album. v.p., circa 1850-; no.110; (1 item, 16 cm. Leather bound album with brass clasps)
  Ex-libris: Albert Boni.
- New Zealand. v.p., circa 1890; no.111; (1 item. 31 × 25 cm. Photograph album with 57 photographs on 14 leaves)
  Included are portraits of Maoris with tattooed faces, featherwork cloaks and other traditional Maori clothing, and also views of the country and the white settlers. Some of the photographs are signed Iles or J.R.
- Australia. v.p., 1885; no.112; (1 item. 28 × 38 cm. Photograph album with 43 photographs on 34 leaves)
  Cover title. Included are panoramic views of Melbourne, Blue Mountain, Kattomba Valley, the Great Zig-zag Railroad, and the Fish River Caves. Many photographs are signed Caney & Company, Mt. Victoria, and there is a portrait of J. Wilson from Caney & Company.
- Mexico City and environs., circa 1880-1895; no.113; (Photograph album with 10 images)
  Views of the cathedrals facade with people posing, landscapes, street scenes, a woman either making tortillas or grinding corn over stone, water carriers with ceramic containers, independence events, and Mount Popocatepetl.
  Visible file of the photos is available.
- Photographie. Paris., circa 1870s; no.114; (1 vol., 38 × 30 cm. Photograph album)
  Bois de Boulogne (photographs of paintings by Justin Ouvrié), ruins of St. Cloud, and a few views of unidentified chateaux.
- Snapshots of Ireland and Europe., 1911-1914; no.115; (14 vol. 12 × 17 cm. Photograph albums with velox[?] prints 7.5 × 10 or 5 × 8 cm. on double weight paper bound in Morocco)
  The work of an amateur photographer depicting:
  1911- Algeria, Holland, Germany.
  1912- Corsica, Italy.
  1913- Parknasilla, Thuringia, Rügen, Brandenburg.
  1914- Rhine, Domburg, Cara del Mare, Provence.
- Burmese photographs. v.p., circa 1868; no.116; (1 vol., 34 × 27 cm. Photograph album. 24 images, 19 × 27 cm. and smaller, bound in 3/4 Morocco)
  Cover title.
- Athens. Athens, Greece., circa 1870s; no.117; (1 vol., 40 × 33 cm. Photograph album with 26 images 21 × 26 cm., bound in full Morocco)
  Cover title. By John Dale & Company. A random selection of commercial photographs numbered but not signed in the plate, identified in manuscript on the mount.
- Torino. Torino, Italy., circa 1860s[?]; no.118; (1 vol., 30.5 × 44 cm. Photograph album. 29 images, 19 × 25 cm.)
  Cover title. The images are imprinted Maggi, or else have no imprint at all.
- Excavations at Civita Lavinia (the ancient Lanuvium) untertaken by H.E. Sir J. Savile Lumley, G.C.B. Lanuvio, Italy., 1884-1889; no.119; (1 item, 40 × 54 cm. Portfolio of photographs with 26 images, 18 × 25 cm.)
  Cover title. Depicting the excavations and antiquities of the Roman ruins at Lanuvio.
- Italy. v.p., 1890s[?]; no.120; (4 vol. 26 × 37 cm. Photograph album with 297 mounted photographs, most of them 19 × 25 cm.)
  Views of Italian streets, buildings, landscapes, and art objects, all issued under the same imprint.
- Napoli. Naples, Italy., circa 1895; no.121; (1 vol. 26 × 34.5 cm. Photograph album with 25 images, 20 × 25 cm., in velum, gold-stamped album)
  Cover title. Views include Pompei and other sites in the vicinity of Naples.
- European views. v.p. (Italy and France)., circa 1890s[?]; no.122; (1 vol. 28 × 39 cm. Photograph album with 84 views, 19.5 × 25.5 cm.)
  City streets, buildings, and art objects in Italy and France.
- Fotografier Samlede Paa Rejse, 1884-87. v.p., v.d.; no.123; (1 vol. [30 × 41 cm.] Photograph album)
  Cover title: European travel album with views in Austria, Italy, and Germany.
- Paris., March-May 1871; no.124/1-2; (2 Photograph albums: vol.1 [26 × 35 cm.] with 41 images, 17 documents and letters; vol.2 [39 × 34 cm.] with 25 images and 3 documents)
  Cover titles. The albums relate to the Paris Commune. Many of the documents are issued to James Saumarez, attaché to the British Embassy, and suggest the albums may have been assembled by him. The photographs show the barricaded streets and damaged buildings of the city.
- Tintype album. n.p., circa 1870s[?]; no.125; (1 vol. [4.5 × 8 cm.] 48 "gem" tintypes in a 12 leaf photograph album, Morocco tooled in gold, with a brass clasp)
  Gift of Brooke Whiting, 1976.
- Italian art. v.p. (Italy)., 1880s[?]; no.126; (3 vol. 34 × 27 cm. Photograph albums)
  Photographs of paintings and sculpture in the galleries of Italy.
  1) Florence, 83 photographs.
  2) Rome, 80 photographs, including some views of the city.
  3) Venice, Naples, etc., 125 photographs.
- Italian art study collection. v.p. (Italy)., circa 1890s[?]; no.127; (6 boxes, 1148 photographs. 20 × 25 cm. Photographs mounted on cloth)
  Photographs of paintings, sculpture, and decorative architectural detail, most of them by Alinari, Angerson, and Brogi.
  A register of the collection is on file.
- Some examples of American paintings in the collection William T. Evans, Wentworth Manor. Montclair, New Jersey., 1904; no.128; (1 item. 27 × 39 cm. Photograph album with 50 velox images, 19 × 24.5 cm.)
  With an exhibit program tipped in.
- Views of European and Near Eastern cities. v.p., circa 1880s[?]; no.129; (12 boxes of Photograph albums with mounted photographs, 26.5 × 35 cm.)
  The collection consists of disbound photograph albums containing photographs of exterior and interior views of public buildings, churches, park and countryside scenes, statues, and monuments, many identified in the plate.
  Gift of Paramount Studios.
  A register of the collection is in the Collections Files.
- Album de photographie. n.p. (France?)., circa 1850; no.145; (2 vol. 29 cm. Photograph album with approximately 120 Calotypes and albumen prints)
  Floral still life arrangements, garden views, paintings, and sculpture, probably the work of an amateur experimenter.
- Members of the Los Angeles University Club. Los Angeles., circa 1915; no.146; (1 vol. 25 × 43 cm. Photograph album with 58 portraits, approximately 15 × 9 cm.)
  Signed by Prince.
  A register is in the collection file.
- The 19th century view of England and Italy. v.p., 1881-1882; no.147; (5 albums. 35 × 48 cm. Approximately 900 images)
  Professional photographs collected on a grand tour, with "Sellar" stamped in gold on each album.
  1) Scenery of Ireland, Scotland, and England.
  2) Paintings in European galleries.
  3-4) Scenery of Italy.
  5) Sculpture in European galleries.
  Index in the Collection folder.
  Gift of Mr. Lee Perkal, 1976.
- Theatrical carte-de-visite album. v.p., circa 1860s; no.148; (1 item. 26 × 23 cm. Annotated photograph album with 77 images)
  Containing portraits of stage and opera personalities by some of the outstanding photographers of the period.
- Theatrical portrait album. London., circa 1880s; no.149; (1 item. 27 × 20.5 cm. Photograph album with 43 portraits)
  Taken specially for "The Theatre," mostly by Barrand or by the St. James Photographic Company.
- Theater program album. New York., 1887; no.150; (1 item. 22.5 × 29 cm. Photograph album with 10 images)
  Theatrical portraits together with related theater programs.
- Music box album. v.p., 1890s; no.151; (1 item. 29 × 36 cm. Photograph album with 38 images)
  Theatrical portraits mounted in a slotted album with a music box in the base.
- Vaticano. Rome., [1880s?]; no.152; (1 vol., 24 × 33.5 cm. Photograph album with 26 hand-colored photographs)
  Cover title. The paintings and sculpture in the Vatican.
- Fountains and tombs in Italy and France. v.p., 1870s[?]; no.153; (1 vol., 54 × 45 cm. Photograph album with photographs mounted on canvas)
  Showing examples of sculptural details of fountains and tombs, mostly of an earlier date.
- Ruins and sculpture of Italy. v.p., 1880s[?]; no.154; (1 vol., 54 × 45 cm. Photograph album with photographs mounted on canvas)
  Showing panoramas of Italian ruins and views of statues and bas-reliefs.
- Architectural detail. v.p. (Europe)., 1880s[?]; no.155; (1 vol., 54 × 45 cm. Photograph album with photographs mounted on canvas)
  Mostly close views of European architectural detail. The album also includes views of columns and statues.
- [Collection of photographs relating to Benito Mussolini]. v.p. (Italy)., 1930; no.156; (124 items. 18 × 24 cm. Photographs)
  Public relations and press release photographs, unmounted, most of them showing Mussolini at state functions, making speeches, reviewing troops, etc.
- Indian craftsmen. London., circa 1880; no.157; (40 Mounted photographs of watercolor drawings in a portfolio)
  Similar in style and subject to other works of John Lockwood Kipling (1837-1911), father of Rudyard Kipling.
  Signed in the drawing J.L.K.
- Walkowitz's drawings., no.158; (75 snapshots mounted on black paper, many fading)
  Ex-libris: Henry Goldman.
  Boxed with 94/145.
- Mexico., circa 1900-1910; no.159; (53 photographs)
  Scenic views of city and country life, many identified in the plate. Included is a portrait of General Porifino Diaz, President of Mexico.
- Portraits contemporains., circa 1868-1871; no.160; (Photograph album with 200 carte-de-visite portraits, bound in green Morocco with brass fittings and with monogram JA on a brass plate)
  Europeans of distinction, including royalty, composers, artists, performers, and members of the Commune.
- Long Beach Family., circa 1909/1920; no.161; (Photograph album, 100pp.)
  Containing family groups, some views of early automobiles, and a number of shots of 1918 Farmerettes and other girls in uniform.
  Gift of Dr Richard Lingenfelter, 1977.
- A-mi-Qut-a-qus (Yellow Sky). Yuma., 1904-1920; no.162; (Photograph album)
  Laid in is a Manuscript description of the Indian hermit, Yellow Sky.
- Mountain trip. Northern Luzon (Philippines)., circa 1910; no.*163; (Photograph album with 165 photographs)
  Portraits of tribesmen and scenes of tribal activities in Northern Luzon. The album was a presentation copy from Cameron Forbes (Governor of the Philippines) to Larz Anderson (U.S. Secretary of War).
  Another copy: 1 reel 35 mm. negative microfilm.
- Prize winning prints from Photography Magazine international picture contest. New York: Pavel Laboratories., circa 1950s; no.164; (2 packages of mounted photographs, 51 images [47 black and white; four color])
  Prize winners are in package 1.
  Gift of LACO Incorporated, 1977.
- St. Pétersbourg. Russia., ca 1860s[?]; no.165; (1 album of 12 images, identified in Manuscript)
  Boxed with 94/160.
- Japanese photograph album., circa 1890s; no.166; (36 hand-colored images in a slotted album)
  Country scenery, street and domestic views.
  Shelved with 94/156.
- Yellowstone snapshots. Yellowstone National Park., 1927; no.167; (Photograph album with approximately 100 snapshots)
  Mostly wildflowers and animals. One snapshot is of Calvin Coolidge and party on a visit.
  Ex-libris: Horace Albright.
- Carte-de-visite album. England., circa 1860/70s; no.168; (1 vol.)
  Family portraits, identified in Manuscript on the mounts. Names include Copeman, Spurrell, Hare and others.
- Hawaiian photograph album., circa 1880s; no.169; (Photograph album with 12 sepia images)
  Views of native activities and island scenery.
- Views of Burma., circa 1897; no.170; (Photograph album. 34 images)
  Views in Mandalay, the Mogok ruby mines, Yenangyet etc.
- Los Angeles photograph album., circa 1880-1900; no.171
  Approximately 800 images of the Los Angeles area, sepia gelatine, some Manuscript identification throughout.
- Rio de Janeiro., circa 1880s[?]; no.172; (Photograph album with 100 images)
  Panoramic views of Rio de Janeiro including public buildings, market scenes, natural landmarks, the Corcovado railway, botanical gardens, Pao de Assucar, and Ile das Flechas.
- Greenfield, Ohio, public schools. William B. Inner, architect; photographs by Henry Stark. Greenfield, Ohio., 1926; no.173; (Photograph album with 58 images, mounted)
  Showing Edward Lee McClain High School, Vocational School, and Elementary School, interiors and exteriors.
  Gift of Bill Cartwright, 1979.
- Various South American scenes taken on the cruise of the S.S. Nieuw Amsterdam around South America., 1939; no.174; (84 images)
  Panoramic views of major cities in Latin America, their monuments and ancient ruins, public buildings, street scenes, and some portraits of native people.
- Italy., circa 1920; no.175; (Photograph album)
  Commercial photographs.
- World War 1., circa 1917/18; no.176; (Photograph album)
  Snapshots and postcards taken in France and Italy by a German soldier. A typewritten list in German identifies the images.
- An unidentified family of means. New York City., circa 1910; no.177; (2 items, Photograph album with 50 snapshots)
  Many views of Fifth Avenue Central Park, and an Aero meet at Belmont Park.
  Gift of Wilbur Jordan Smith, 1979.
  Boxed with 94/174.
- Survey of Wilshire Boulevard. Los Angeles., circa 1955; no.178; (5 boxes, ca. 900 photographs in 19 binders)
  Glossy photographs, probably used by a realtor, showing each of the buildings on Wilshire Blvd from Grand Avenue through Beverly Hills. Some volumes are interleaved with real estate information. A register is in the Collections File.
- Fattoria di S. Andrea in Percussina, proprieta della Eccuma pasa Elena Demidoff. Raccolta delle vedute principali relative ai danni causati del terremoto del 18 Maggio 1895., no.179; (Photograph album with 29 mounted prints)
  Identified on the mounts in Manuscript. They show the destruction caused by an earthquake to the holdings of the Princess Demidoff in the small town of S. Andrea in Percussina, Italy, a few kilometers from Florence.
- Scotty's Castle. Death Valley, California., circa 1930s; no.180; (Photograph album with 25 photographs)
  Included are amateur snapshots of points of interest in Death Valley. The Frashers' Fotos are almost all interior views of Scotty's Castle.
- Sakhalin, Siberia., circa 1900; no.181; (Photograph album with 116 albumen prints mounted 2 to a page)
  Identified in a contemporary many, many of them in Russian as well as English. Included are views of towns, bridges, the railroad, ethnic types, interiors of hospitals, churches, museums etc.
  Gift of John and Carol Steinberg, 1979.
- People of the South Pacific., circa 1900s[?]; no.182; (Photograph album)
  Headhunters and cannibals of the Pacific Islands and Australasia. Included also are scenes of beheading during the Shanghai riots of 1927. Nilsson, who was a unicyclist, traveled extensively.
  Boxed with 94/58-60.
- Snow Crystal Photomicrographs., circa 1931; no.*183; (Photograph album with 200 images)
  Used to illustrate 'Snow Crystals (New York: McGraw-Hill, 1931), a work with a brief text by William Jackson Humphreys.
- Philippines., 1915; no.*184; (Snapshot album)
  Ex-libris: D.A.L. Day.
  Negative microfilm reel available.
- New Zealand (Maoriland). C.G.G., March 1886; no.*185; (56 mounted sepia images)
  Most titled in the plates and signed by various photographers (C.G., Burton Brothers, Wheeler & Sons). Scenic views include the pink and white terraces which were destroyed by the eruption of Mt Tarawerea (June 10, 1886) and portraits of Maoris in native dress.
- Views of Egypt., circa 1880; no.*186/1-2; (Two volumes)
  Included in vol.2 are two photographs of the Vanderbilt party on a trip down the Nile (1887), probably taken at the time the albums were assembled. Identified in Manuscript are Consuelo in her early teens, her brother Harold, and her mother, Alva Vanderbilt, later Mrs Oliver Belmont.
  Ex-libris: Oliver Hazard Perry Belmont; Library of Architecture and Allied Arts.
- Pacific Electric Railway Company's laying of tracks. Los Angeles., 1899; no.187; (Photograph album)
- Princesse-album (Holland)., no.188; (96 photographic postcards affixed in a 24-leaf slotted album, eight additional photographs laid in)
  Portraits of the Dutch royal family beginning with Princess Juliana in her early teens and continuing through her wedding, World War 2, and the growing up of her children.
  Shelved with 94/178, box 3.
- Architectural views., no.189; (8 boxes)
  From the working collection of the Library of Architecture and Allied Arts. A register of the collection is in the Collections file.
- Views and flowers of the Holyland. Jerusalem., circa 1920s; no.190; (Floral collage)
  The olive wood cover, hand-carved with an inlaid border, was done by Bet Bezalel Art School, Jerusalem, and is inscribed in Hebrew: 'Gift of Talmud Torah Vi-Yeshivah Haye 'Olam.' Also included are two photographs of the school and its students.
  Gift of Shimeon Brisman, 1980.
  Boxed with 94/177.
- Tjandi Mission-Post and Orphanage. Dutch East Indies., circa 1930; no.191; (Photograph album)
  Showing interior and exterior views of a Catholic mission, the brothers, and the orphans in their care.
- Hopi Indians. Arizona., circa 1901; no.192; (Photograph album with 24 mounted images and two additional images laid in)
  Photographs of ceremonial dances, pueblos, and daily life scenes.
  Gift of Beatrice H. Whittlesey.
- California[?]., circa 1900; no.193; (Snapshot album)
  Family snapshots in and around Los Angeles[?].
- Views of Owens Valley and vicinity., 1905/06; no.*194; (Photograph album with 28 images, panoramic views)
  Stowell was a land developer whose involvement in the Owens Valley water story is the source of Harold Bell Wright's The Winning of Barbara Worth.
  Ex-libris: Nathan William Stowell.
  Gift of Mrs. George Leslie Ellsworth.
- Caribbee Islands., 1884-1885; no.*195; (Photograph album with 113 photographs)
  With Manuscript identification throughout.
  Ex-libris: Josiah Foster Flagg (1835-1928) of Santa Barbara, a civil engineer who headed projects in South America and the West Indies.
- Garden, Iron Work, and Furniture., no.*196; (20 vol. of photographs in 11 packages)
  vol.1-4) Gardens (U.S.).
  vol.5) Italian furniture.
  vol.6) Gardens (Italy).
  vol.7) Gardens, Iron and Bronze Work (Italy).
  vol.8 Gardens, Iron and Bronze Work (England).
  vol.9) Gardens, Iron and Bronze Work (France).
  vol.10) Rockefeller Gardens.
  vol.11) Miscellaneous Iron and Bronze Work.
- Philippines., circa 1910; no.197; (Photograph album with 35 images [12 × 17 cm.] and 15 smaller snapshots)
  With typed captions in the nature of a travelogue.
- The Levant., no.198; (1 box, 60 mounted photographs on 35 leaves - 25 leaves appear to be from one album)
  Included are photographs by J.B. Sebah, H. Arnoux, Zangaki, Bonfils, and G. Lekegian.
- Samoa, New Zealand, Ceylon, India, and Europe., circa 1890; no.*199; (Photograph album with 93 images)
  Probably collected on a tour.
- Portraits of early California residents. Los Angeles, San Francisco and San Jose., circa 1860-70; no.200; (155 images removed from an album)
  Most are carte-de-visites inscribed to Dofa Chacon. A few are identified (Valentine Wolfenstein; Henri Penelon; M.A. Franklin; freaks, deformities, human curiosities).